gla.ac.uk 2017-11-04

# University of Glasgow - Legal statements - Privacy

This statement outlines the information gathered during your visit to the University of Glasgow's central web servers and explains how this information is treated. If you choose to request information from this site you will need to pass personal data to the University through this site. Where you actively provide personal data to the University [for example, by completing a web form] this data will be used only for the service you have requested unless you consent otherwise at the time of submitting the data.

### Data Protection Act

The gathering, storage, use, release and disposal of personal information is regulated by the Data Protection Act 1998. The University's policy and guidelines with respect to the Act, are published by the Data Protection and Freedom of Information Office.

### Surveillance and monitoring

Staff, students and visitors should be aware that the University operates CCTV and similar equipment to monitor safety and security and to aid the prevention and detection of crime. In addition, the University may monitor postal, telecommunications, data communications, and other communications as permitted by the relevant legislation and University Regulations. Pleas see: Monitoring & Surveillance (CCTV/WebCam).

### Freedom of Information (Scotland) Act

The records of the University of Glasgow are subject to the terms of the Freedom of Information (Scotland) 2002 Act. The Act gives individuals a general right of access to all types of recorded information, of any age, held by the University. The University's policy and guidelines with respect to the Freedom of Information Act (Scotland) 2002 are published by the Data Protection and Freedom of Information Office.

## The information collected

### Log files

The University's website does not automatically capture or store personal data from visitors to the site, other than to log your IP address and session information. Session information includes the time and duration of your visit to the site, the files requested, and the browser used. This information will only be accessed by authorised persons of the University of Glasgow or its agents. The information will be retained by the University and will only be used for the purpose of (a) managing the site system, (b)  the identification of broken links, and (c) for statistical and audit purposes.

### Web Forms

You may occasionally be asked to provide personal information to gain access to specific services. By supplying such information the client consents to the University storing the information for the stated purpose. The information is held by the University in accordance with the provisions of the Data Protection Act 1998.

This privacy policy does not cover the links within this site to other non-University sites nor the content of external internet sites.

Cookies are small text files passed to your computer by the web server via your browser, and may be used to collect information to help identify you and prepare customised pages for you. Cookies may remain on your computer either for the duration of the session or indefinitely. You can configure most standard web browsers to refuse cookies.

The University and our authorised agents make use of Google Analytics to produce anonymised statistics on website usage: to help us to improve our site and the experience of our users. Google Analytics uses cookies in this process. 

Occasionally, we give users the opportunity to save settings for viewing pages. This involves the setting of a cookie. We do not track such cookies. 

Information on cookies can be obtained from [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

### Google Analytics

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google").  Google Analytics uses "cookies", which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.

### Advertising Cookies

We also set cookies for advertising or remarketing purposes: enabling us to serve more tailored advertising as well as helping improve our site for users.

Google uses cookies like NID and SID to help customize advertising on Google properties, like Google Search. Such cookies remember your most recent searches, your previous interactions with our website, search results, and engagement with our advertising. This helps us to show you customized advertising on Google.

We also use cookies for advertising we serve across the web. The main advertising cookie on non-Google sites is called ‘id’ and it is stored in browsers under the domain doubleclick.net. With the DoubleClick product, a cookie called ‘__gadvertising’ may be set on the domain of the site you are visiting. Unlike cookies that are set on Google's own domains, this cookie can't be read by Google when you're on other sites. It serves purposes such as measuring interactions with the advertising on that domain and preventing the same advertising from being shown to you too many times.

Some of our other cookies may be used to measure conversion events as well. For example, DoubleClick and Google Analytics cookies may also be used for this purpose.

We also use the MediaMath provider to deliver advertising on behalf of the University. Details of their policies and opt-out mechanisms can be found at [www.mediamath.com/privacy-policy](http://www.mediamath.com/privacy-policy/)

More information on cookies can be obtained from [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).
